A Guide to the Personal Papers of thomas E. Derr, 1951-1967
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
Personal Papers of thomas E. Derr, 1951-1967
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
RG 339
2 boxes.
Derr, Thomas E.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
The collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Thomas Derr in 2002.
Biographical Information
Thomas E. Derr graduated from Stratford Junior High School (class of 1964) and Washington-Lee High School (class of 1967) in Arlington, now called Washington Liberty High School. He later resided in Bristol, Virginia.
Scope and Content
Record Group 339 houses the personal papers of Thomas E. Derr, formerly of Arlington, Virginia. The record group measures approximately 1.5 linear feet and dates from 1951 through 1967, with the bulk from 1961 through 1967. Types of material include school publications, school and sports memorabilia, and clippings.
The materials appear to have been collected while he was a student. Most of the materials concern team sports played at the two schools, especially basketball and rowing, and include sporting event programs and numerous clippings. Some clippings are from local newspapers, and many are both undated and from unidentified papers. There are also some general school publications and memorabilia unrelated to sports, and some sports publications not related to either school.
Arrangement
RG 339 is organized into two series by the two schools attended. All folder titles were created by the processor.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
For more information about Arlington Public Schools in general and Stratford Junior High and Washington Lee High Schools specifically, see RG 7, Arlington Public Schools.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Public schools -- United States.; Arlington Public Schools (Arilngton, Va.); Arlington (Va.); Arlington County (Va.)
Contents List
- Stratford Junior High School Materials
  - Arlington School News, 1957-1960 (Box 1)
  - Stratford Junion High School PTA Handbooks, 1961-1962, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Stratford Junion High School Student Handbook, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - The Signpost, 1951-1964 (Box 1)
  - Stratford Junior High School Sports and Other Memorabilia, 1962-1964 (Box 1)
  - Stratford Junior High School Sports Clippings, 1961-1964 (Box 1)
- Washington-Lee High School Materials
  - Student Driving Manual, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Crossed Sabres, October 1964 - January 1965 (Box 1)
  - Crossed Sabres, September 1965 - June 1967 (Box 1)
  - Penman, 1964-1967 (Box 1)
  - Track & Field News, 1964-1965 (Box 2)
  - Track & Field News, 1966-1967 (Box 2)
  - Sports Programs, Washington-Lee, 1961-1967 (Box 2)
  - Sports Programs, Other, 1966-1967 (Box 2)
  - Washington-Lee Sports and Other Memorabilia, 1963-1965 (Box 2)
  - Washington-Lee Sports and Other Memorabilia, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Clippings re: Washington-Lee Sports, 1964-1967 (1) (Box 2)
  - Clippings re: Washington-Lee Sports, 1964-1967 (2) (Box 2)
  - Cavalier Daily Issues, April 1, November 5, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Issue of Go, August 18, 1967 (Box 2)